personalityhacker.com 2019-05-31

# Privacy Policy — Personality Type and Personal Growth | Personality Hacker

_Last modified: May 30, 2018_

_We want to be responsible in how we deal with you, and your data.   We promise you this:_

  1. We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.
  2. We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what information we keep on you, and what is permanently deleted.
  3. We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  4. We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our services.

We kept this policy simple so it’s easy to understand what information we collect, how we use it, and what choices you have about it. You should read the whole policy, but here’s a very brief summary of the good parts:

  * We don’t sell your personal data to anyone. 
  * All we know about you is what you share by visiting and exploring our website. We don’t collect any of your personal information from any third parties, so it’s completely up to you what you share. 
  * When you use our website, even if you aren’t logged in, we receive some personal information from you like the type of device you’re using and your IP address. You can choose to share additional information with us by creating an account. We use this information for improving our services and for keeping our website functional and secure.
  * You are free to opt in and out of our newsletters, update your account details, or delete it entirely at any time. You can also ask us to give you a copy of the information you’ve submitted.
  * We use your answers to our surveys, tests, and other tools to determine what content is relevant to you and to improve our understanding of personality traits. You’re completely free to decide which surveys to take and which tools to explore.
  * If you have any questions or comments regarding this policy, please don’t hesitate to [get in touch](https://personalityhacker.com/contact/)!

## 1\. How Do We Collect Information?

First, we collect, store, and use information you share on our website. This includes your e-mail address, comments, and any other information you choose to enter on the website.

If you post personal information of another person on our website, you must make sure you have that person’s consent to both the disclosure and the processing of their personal data in accordance with this privacy policy. That’s your responsibility.

Second, if you purchase something for yourself or for anyone else on our website, we’ll collect payment and tax information, contact and delivery information, and details of what you bought.

Finally, we record certain technical information whenever you use our website. This includes information about your device and about your visits to and use of our website, such as your IP address, browser type and version, page views, etc.

We also use cookies (small encrypted data files stored and sent by your browser whenever you visit our website) to store and retrieve your login status, personality test results, and various website settings. Some of the cookies are account-specific while others are not. For more information about cookies, please see the following section.

### Cookies

Most of the functionality on our website (such as viewing your personality test results or logging in) requires cookies. By using our website, you consent to our use of cookies as described in this policy.

We use “persistent” cookies on our website. Persistent cookies will remain stored on your device until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.

We use cookies to enable our website to recognise you (as distinct from other users) when you visit and keep track of your preferences in relation to your use of our website.

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. This third party service may use cookies and other technologies to collect technical data on your behavior and your device (such as your device’s IP address or screen size). For further details, please see [Google’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). You can also opt out of [Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en) tracking at any time.

Most browsers allow you to reject all cookies, while some browsers allow you to reject just third party cookies. Blocking all cookies will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites, including ours.

### Whether Information Has to Be Provided by You and Why

The provision of contact and other relevant information is required from you to enable us to communicate with you and to provide the services available on our website. We’ll inform you at the point of collecting information from you (including via this Privacy Policy), whether you’re required to provide the information to us.

If you don’t provide the information requested we may not be able to provide the services which require the use of this information (e.g., certain features or assessments).

## 2\. How Do We Use the Information We Collect?

We use the information we collect to provide you with our services as well as content that’s relevant and personal to you. Consequently, it’s necessary for us to use your information to:

  * send you your personality test results, if you request them;
  * send you account-related messages, such as password recovery e-mails;
  * identify you and ensure the security of your account – e.g., by verifying that you own the e-mail address linked to your account;
  * collect payments from you and send you e-mails with your order details, if you decide to purchase something from us;
  * provide you with content and services relevant to you – e.g., information for people with your personality type;
  * respond to your questions or complaints, or to complaints made about your use of our website.

We have a legitimate interest in using your information in these ways. It’s necessary for us to do that to make our services and content as relevant to you as possible, and that’s in both of our interests.

We also have a legitimate interest in making you happy, and making our website, content and podcasts as awesome as possible.

So we use this information to:

  * conduct analytics on how you use our website in order to better understand your needs and to optimize our service and experience. We use a third party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns (for example, how much time you spent reading your personality test results). We’ve already mentioned these services in the Cookies section above.
  * This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We don’t make, and don’t allow Google to make, any attempt to match such information with personal data we hold about you.
  * improve our website and develop new functionality. For example, if the majority of respondents in one of our surveys say they struggle finding work-life balance, we would take note.
  * Analyze information to learn about personality traits. For instance, your responses to our surveys could help us notice a correlation between Introversion and anxiety. The data you supply is anonymize, and access to it is strictly limited. Even our own employees only see data that cannot be connected back to any individually identifying information
  * keep the website secure and prevent fraud – e.g., by logging authentication attempts or activities related to your account;
  * keep both you and other users safe, including working with law enforcement where necessary. So, we might inform the police if something you’ve posted makes us think that it’s highly likely you or someone else is in danger.

Most of what we use your data for is related to our legitimate interests, but in the following circumstances other legal grounds apply to how we process your personal data:

  * where we expressly require consent from you for the processing in question;
  * where we provide services to you as a member – in which case we’ll have a contract  (like if you purchase a course or other product) with you for this and we’ll process your data in accordance with our contract with you. In particular, our contract allows us to retain and delete data in ways which override certain rights you may otherwise have had if we were relying on consent or our legitimate interests for the data processing in question.
  * where another legal ground applies (which will probably never happen) – for example if we’re required to process the information by law.

Also, we’ll only use your information with your consent:

  * to send you email newsletters, if you’ve specifically agreed to receive them and confirmed that by clicking a link in the verification email. You can unsubscribe from our emails at any time by clicking a link at the bottom of any message.

You can withdraw your consent at any time.

**We won’t provide your personal information to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing by those parties.**

## 3\. Do We Transfer Your Information Elsewhere?

As a worldwide digital service, we need to work with a number of providers, in order to be able to operate our website and to make our services available online. 

We limit access to your personal information to those members of our staff who have a business reason for knowing such information. If you’d like further information on this, please [contact us](https://personalityhacker.com/contact/).

Here’s a list of third party providers (and links to their privacy policies) we’ll share your information with, if necessary:

  * [Infusionsoft](https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy), to deliver our newsletters. We also gather statistics around e-mail opening and clicks to help us monitor and improve our newsletters.
  * [Gmail](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Infusionsoft](https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy), to deliver our non-newsletter e-mails, e.g., when we respond to your messages. Again, we’ll also collect information regarding e-mail delivery and opening rates to improve deliverability and help with troubleshooting. 
  * [SurveyGizmo](https://www.surveygizmo.com/privacy/) and [Google Forms](https://policies.google.com/privacy) to collect survey data.
  * [Novac Solutions](https://novaksolutions.com/legal/) so send your information via API from [SurveyGizmo](https://www.surveygizmo.com/privacy/), to our databases.
  * [Infusionsoft](https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy) and [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full), to process payments and conduct anti-fraud checks. 
  * [Google Sheets](https://policies.google.com/privacy) to organize and analyze anonymized survey data
  * [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy), [MediaTemple](https://mediatemple.net/legal/privacy-policy/), and [WordPress](https://wordpress.org/about/privacy/) to analyze the behaviour of our visitors as well as to host our website, databases, and related assets and services.
  * [Infusionsoft](https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/privacy-policy), to manage and respond to support emails. 
  * [Slack](https://slack.com/privacy-policy) for our everyday communication and planning. 

We’ve listed all our third party providers here to be as transparent as possible.

We use all reasonable security and access control measures to secure our accounts on third party websites and the data stored therein.

Keep in mind that information you publish on our website (such as your profile name or posts) will likely be available anywhere. We can’t prevent the use or misuse of such information by others.

## 4\. How Can You Manage Your Information?

Go to our [Personal Information Request Page](https://personalityhacker.com/personal-information-request/).  Also, you can always send us an email at support@personalityhacker.com, and ask us to edit your information.

If you have an account to access our paid courses and products, you can access and change your information in the My Account section.

If you delete your profile, we’ll anonymize your user record, removing your e-mail address, name, age, etc.

We won’t, however, delete your comments, your anonymized responses to our tests and surveys, log records, and other similar data. We need to keep that data for a number of reasons, such as preserving the integrity of our data, or ensuring the security of our website, and the retention of this data is necessary for us to provide our services to you and others.

If you decide to delete your profile, please make sure you first save any information you’d like to keep. Once the profile is gone, it’s gone 

You can also ask us to correct any personal data you have provided to us, or to remove specific personally identifying information from our website. E.g., if you would like to change the email address on your account, we’ll do that.

## 5\. How and When Do We Share Your Information?

If you post content in our comment sections or anywhere else on our website where that’s possible, you should assume that anyone will be able to read that information – unless it’s clear that access to such information will be limited to yourself or a specific user (e.g., comments sent from the [contact us page](https://personalityhacker.com/contact/)). 

Our staff, agents, suppliers, and subcontractors may also need to have access to your information where that’s necessary. This applies to any member of our group of companies – e.g., our subsidiaries and our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries.

For example, if you ask us to fix a misbehaving subscription, someone from our team will need to access your account to do that. However, access to your personal data is strictly limited and monitored, with sensitive details (such as your password) securely encrypted.

Besides that, there are also certain other circumstances where we may disclose your personal information:

  * where we’re required to do so by law or in connection with any ongoing, prospective, or reasonably likely (in our opinion) legal proceedings;
  * where we need to establish, exercise, or defend our legal rights (e.g., providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention);
  * if we’re engaged in a merger, reorganisation, or any similar proceeding requiring the transfer of your information – we’d then share your information with a party involved in such a process (for example, a potential purchaser);
  * if we have strong reason to believe that you or someone else is in immediate physical danger.

We don’t have ads on our website, and we don’t share your data with online advertisers. As a general rule, except as discussed above, we don’t share your personal information with any third parties.

## 6\. How Long Do We Keep Your Information?

We keep your information only for as long as we need it to provide services to you. This also applies to any other parties that we share your information with.

Here are some examples of categories of data along with their periods of retention:

  * payment and order data, including relevant access logs – 10 years;
  * activity logs, minus the above – 1 year;
  * transient activity records, such as e-mail invites or password reset requests – unlimited;
  * account details – unlimited;
  * We’ll regularly delete accounts that aren’t linked to any meaningful activity and have been inactive for more than 4 months
  * content submitted to our website, such as comments or forum posts – unlimited.

We’ll depersonalize your information or remove it entirely from our systems once we no longer need it to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations, or for other purposes described in this policy.

## 7\. What Can You Ask Us to Do with Your Information?

Under the GDPR you have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:

  * fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your personal information that this Privacy Policy is already designed to address;
  * access to your personal information and to certain other supplementary information;
  * require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold;
  * require the erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situations;
  * receive the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and have the right to transmit that data to a third party in certain situations;
  * object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketing;
  * object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you;
  * object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information;
  * otherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances;
  * withdraw your consent to our processing where we are relying on consent as the lawful basis for the processing in question;
  * right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

If you’d like to exercise any of those rights, please [e-mail us](mailto:support@personalityhacker.com). Keep in mind you’ll need to send the request from the e-mail address associated with your account in order for us to process it. We won’t be able to confirm you’re the account owner otherwise.

As already mentioned above, if you’d like to unsubscribe from our newsletter, you can also click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the e-mail. That’s usually immediate, but in rare cases it may take a few days for this to take place.

## 8\. How Do We Secure Your Information?

We take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse, or alteration of your personal information. For instance, we store this information on our secure (password and firewall-protected) servers, encrypt traffic to and from the website, and anonymize personal information where possible.

Still, we can’t guarantee complete security of data sent over the internet – for example, someone may discover a vulnerability in the encryption protocol that we use, your internet service provider may record the data you send, and so on. Please be careful any time you post sensitive data.

## 9\. How Can You Get in Touch with Us?

The best way to get in touch with us is via e-mail (support@personalityhacker.com).

We, Personality Hacker LLC, are the data controller responsible for the information collected on our website. 

Our physical address is:  
PO Box 3081  
Gettysburg, Pennsylvania 17325  
United States (772) 444-2257

## 10\. Extra Credit

You’re responsible for keeping your password and other login details confidential. Don’t share this information with anyone, because whoever has it will have full access to all your information on our website.

Some of our articles and website sections contain links to other websites. We aren’t responsible for the privacy policies or practices of those websites.

We may update this privacy policy from time to time by posting a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you’re ok with any changes.
